<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>  on Sri Ray | sricola</title>
    <link>https://sricola.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in   on Sri Ray | sricola</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sricola.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2020: Exploring The United States</title>
      <link>https://sricola.com/blog/cross-country/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sricola.com/blog/cross-country/</guid>
      <description>Sunset Among Joshua Trees Joshua Tree National Park, California
 The Hottest Place on Earth Death Valley, California
 Pandemic Ghost Land Brooklyn Bridge, New York City, New York
 Gateway To The West St. Louis, Missouri
 Red Rock Arch Bryce Canyon National Park, Utah
 Arguably The Best Icecream In The World Flapadoodles, Rochester, Minnesota
 The Grand Tetons Grand Teton National Park, Wyoming
 The Finest Display Of Human Arrogance Las Vegas, Nevada</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYC MTA Ridership over COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://sricola.com/blog/mta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sricola.com/blog/mta/</guid>
      <description>The New York City Transit Authority (MTA) releases weekly data on the number of entries and exits at each of its subway stations. This analysis is based on the data retrieved from the following weeks
 Week of January 19 - &amp;ldquo;normal week&amp;rdquo; before the outbreak, used as a control Week of March 8 - week before NYC placed various restrictions Week of March 15  What data is being analysed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LISA, 2019</title>
      <link>https://sricola.com/talks/lisa19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sricola.com/talks/lisa19/</guid>
      <description>Talked about hiring remote and hiring everywhere! And how to maintain a healthy team while leveraging the distributed benefits.
Download Slides PDF</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://sricola.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 20:16:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sricola.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>Get in touch, even if its a simple, Hi!
Your Name Email Address An email address is required.  Message   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel Scholarship for URMs in Tech</title>
      <link>https://sricola.com/travel-scholarship/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 20:16:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sricola.com/travel-scholarship/</guid>
      <description>One of the best things about being in tech is having the opportunity to work, listen and engage with people from all stratas of society!
This scholarship is a small way for me to share my privilege to enable and push forward another URM&amp;rsquo;s dreams.
If you have a conference, talk and/or (anything else career related) that you would like to attend, and cannot monetarily afford to - I am giving away one free roundtrip flight every quarter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Apple Card: Should You Get One?</title>
      <link>https://sricola.com/blog/apple-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sricola.com/blog/apple-card/</guid>
      <description>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t been stuck under a giant rock, you probably heard that Apple recently announced and made available its own Credit Card. The Apple Card as its being touted is a Credit Card, backed by first time Credit Card issuer - Goldman Sachs. Goldman Sachs is a household name in the financial world and was one of the huge offenders who caused the 2008 Housing Crisis which led to the Great Recession, but thats a rant for another post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SRECon Singapore, 2019</title>
      <link>https://sricola.com/talks/sre-con-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sricola.com/talks/sre-con-2019/</guid>
      <description>Talked about hiring remote and hiring everywhere! And how to maintain a healthy team while leveraging the distributed benefits.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Things I have learnt after flying a Million Miles</title>
      <link>https://sricola.com/blog/after-a-million-miles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sricola.com/blog/after-a-million-miles/</guid>
      <description>Lifetime Flight Map (twitter.com/sricola)
 Be kind to your cabin crew. They literally have your lives in their control. Service is their secondary job — getting you safely from A to B is their primary. And they do their jobs 100% of the time. On the topic of cabin crew, they only get paid on block time — door close to door open. Pre boarding help / stowing your luggage etc is literally volunteer time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expressway Approach into LaGuardia</title>
      <link>https://sricola.com/blog/lga-expressway-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 18:55:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sricola.com/blog/lga-expressway-approach/</guid>
      <description>One of the hardest places to land, in the world!
Disclaimer: I am not a pilot, just an airplane enthusiast. This is all from a passenger’s perspective.
One of the most exciting approaches has to be the Expressway Visual Approach into New York’s LaGuardia airport. It is apparently a very challenging approach that has to be done manually, which is alien to most pilots in this day and age where most of the flying, approaches and landings are all automated by technological awesomeness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>32: A Year in the Life</title>
      <link>https://sricola.com/blog/32-a-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sricola.com/blog/32-a-year/</guid>
      <description>My 32nd trip around the sun, in summary.
flights: 78 | miles in the air: 173,539 | countries: 14 | new countries: 7
December 21, 2017: Rang in my birthday at a Four Points Sheraton in Downtown Manhattan. Was a little inebriated but it doesn’t take much to get me drunk does it?
Spent Christmas in DC with my brother, a dear friend and her dog. Rang in the New Year at a Marriott in Midtown Manhattan, while eating take out Panda Express.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>31: A Year in the Life</title>
      <link>https://sricola.com/blog/31-a-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sricola.com/blog/31-a-year/</guid>
      <description>Completed 30 in SF. Treated myself to nitrogen infused ice cream. Flew to Korea on Christmas Day. Rang in the new year in Hanoi, Vietnam.
January: Went to India to share in an old friend getting married. Flew to Doha and missed my connection to JFK thanks to the confusion caused by Donald Trump’s first attempt at the Muslim ban. Eventually landed in JFK to see people passed out in the arrivals section with signs reading “Wake me up, I am an immigration lawyer and can help”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incident Response</title>
      <link>https://sricola.com/blog/incident-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sricola.com/blog/incident-response/</guid>
      <description>The way you respond to a situation is almost as important as the remedy itself.
Every now and then, while in our line of duty, we are faced with a crisis. This is the story of Speedbird 38.  When the going gets tough, the tough get going. ~ JFKWhen dealing with technology; computers malfunction all the time, code always has bugs and users will always falter. Avoiding all those is nearly impossible, but minimizing the detrimental impact is definitely achievable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Nomad Life: tech in my backpack</title>
      <link>https://sricola.com/blog/tech-in-my-backpack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sricola.com/blog/tech-in-my-backpack/</guid>
      <description>Anything that goes into my backpack has to earn its place there.
This past year, I have lived in 6 continents, 17 countries, 7 time zones and 21 cities. All this while working a full time job, remotely.
Work is my primary goal. Work is what enables me to live this life. So obviously, being connected is the center of my focus. Additionally, I am part of the Infrastructure team at BuzzFeed, which means, I have to be oncall for a week every month and be generally available 24/7, at other times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Altitude 2017</title>
      <link>https://sricola.com/talks/altitude-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sricola.com/talks/altitude-2017/</guid>
      <description>Talked about BuzzFeed&amp;rsquo;s push to giving developers more autonomy and building the tools needed to empower them.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>checklists: an operational gift</title>
      <link>https://sricola.com/blog/checklists/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sricola.com/blog/checklists/</guid>
      <description>No production operation is too small or too big for a checklist. Similarly, no situation is too strenuous for one. Always write one — it ensures smooth process! At BuzzFeed we love lists. I mean, we helped pioneer the list format! Lists are easily digestible and are clear and concise in their meaning. They are no replacement for a long form read, but hey, nobody’s got time to read a leather bound novel by a fireplace during a production operation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Most Wanted iPhone 7 Feature Nobody Talks About</title>
      <link>https://sricola.com/blog/most-wanted-iphone-feature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sricola.com/blog/most-wanted-iphone-feature/</guid>
      <description>Anyone who even remotely follows any technology oriented blog or website is probably well aware of the plethora of rumors and leaks that happen before any major consumer product announcement. This is more so true for rumors and leaks related to Apple. Partly to blame(credit?) for their secrecy when it comes to un-announced products — Apple somehow evokes consumer emotions — on levels that are unheard of. When was the last time CNN covered a queue of people waiting outside the Samsung store, days before a phone launch?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2015: In Black and White</title>
      <link>https://sricola.com/blog/2015-black-and-white/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sricola.com/blog/2015-black-and-white/</guid>
      <description>Aachen Cathedral, Aachen, Germany  Gateway of India, Bombay (Mumbai), India  Dhobi Ghat, the biggest laundromat in the world, Bombay (Mumbai), India  City Hall, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, United States of America  The only double decker tram system in the world, Hong Kong SAR, People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China  Sunrise at 40,000 feet, on approach into London, United Kingdom  Locks of Love, Seoul, Republic of Korea  Manhattan, New York, NY, United States of America  Union Station, Washington, District of Columbia, United States of America  Forrest Fires, California, United States of America  Skyline of Seattle, Washignton, United States of America  View of the skyline from the Bund, Shanghai, People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China  Golden Gate Bridge, San Francisco, California, United States of America  Muir Woods Redwood Trees, California, United States of America  Looking down Market Street, San Francisco, California  Crater Lake, Oregon, United States of America  Wine Barrels, Benzinger Family Wineries, NAPA, California, United States of America  New York Harbor, New York, NY, United States of America  Hayden Planetarium, New York, NY, United States of America  Grand Bazaar, Istanbul, Turkey  Mt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Town in Two Countries - The Baarle Problem</title>
      <link>https://sricola.com/blog/baarle-hertog-baarle-nassau/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2014 18:55:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sricola.com/blog/baarle-hertog-baarle-nassau/</guid>
      <description>With a combined population of less than 8000 - Baarle-Hertog and Baarle-Nassau are off the beaten tourist path. I will admit that not many people would crave to go there. Between getting high in Amsterdam and the beers of Belgium - it is not very uncommon for tourists to completely skip this little gem of International Co-operation.
It is a situation that arose out of a land swap deal during the monarch days of Belgium and the Netherlands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schumacher isn’t my Hero, my Mother is. But he taught me a lot about life.</title>
      <link>https://sricola.com/blog/schumacher-isnt-my-hero/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2014 18:55:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sricola.com/blog/schumacher-isnt-my-hero/</guid>
      <description>The year was 1996. I picked Michael Schumacher as the guy to support - not because I knew a lot about Formula One or the man himself - but because picking him would mean I could pick someone to pit against my brother’s favorite. I was 9 after all. All I wanted to do was annoy my older brother. Man, did I make a great choice or what.
Its all about winning Jerez, European GrandPrix, 1997.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An ode to a dying friend. Blackberry, you will be missed!</title>
      <link>https://sricola.com/blog/an-ode-to-a-dying-friend/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2013 18:55:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sricola.com/blog/an-ode-to-a-dying-friend/</guid>
      <description>I hold Blackberry close to my heart. I accepted my first real job offer on a Blackberry. I read the words “I love you” for the first time ever, in a Blackberry messenger message. I took to obsessively taking photos of food on a Blackberry. I got addicted to twitter on a Blackberry. The list goes on … I broke up with Blackberrys a while back. But, as with any other past relationship, I never meant ill.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
