<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tech on Sri Ray | sricola</title><link>https://sricola.com/categories/tech/</link><description>Recent content in tech on Sri Ray | sricola</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sricola.com/categories/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Apple Card: Should You Get One?</title><link>https://sricola.com/blog/apple-card/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sricola.com/blog/apple-card/</guid><description>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t been stuck under a giant rock, you probably heard that Apple recently announced and made available its own Credit Card. The Apple Card as its being touted is a Credit Card, backed by first time Credit Card issuer - Goldman Sachs. Goldman Sachs is a household name in the financial world and was one of the huge offenders who caused the 2008 Housing Crisis which led to the Great Recession, but thats a rant for another post.</description></item><item><title>Expressway Approach into LaGuardia</title><link>https://sricola.com/blog/lga-expressway-approach/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 18:55:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sricola.com/blog/lga-expressway-approach/</guid><description>One of the hardest places to land, in the world!
Disclaimer: I am not a pilot, just an airplane enthusiast. This is all from a passenger’s perspective.
One of the most exciting approaches has to be the Expressway Visual Approach into New York’s LaGuardia airport. It is apparently a very challenging approach that has to be done manually, which is alien to most pilots in this day and age where most of the flying, approaches and landings are all automated by technological awesomeness.</description></item><item><title>Incident Response</title><link>https://sricola.com/blog/incident-response/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sricola.com/blog/incident-response/</guid><description>The way you respond to a situation is almost as important as the remedy itself.
Every now and then, while in our line of duty, we are faced with a crisis. This is the story of Speedbird 38. When the going gets tough, the tough get going. ~ JFKWhen dealing with technology; computers malfunction all the time, code always has bugs and users will always falter. Avoiding all those is nearly impossible, but minimizing the detrimental impact is definitely achievable.</description></item><item><title>Digital Nomad Life: tech in my backpack</title><link>https://sricola.com/blog/tech-in-my-backpack/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sricola.com/blog/tech-in-my-backpack/</guid><description>Anything that goes into my backpack has to earn its place there.
This past year, I have lived in 6 continents, 17 countries, 7 time zones and 21 cities. All this while working a full time job, remotely.
Work is my primary goal. Work is what enables me to live this life. So obviously, being connected is the center of my focus. Additionally, I am part of the Infrastructure team at BuzzFeed, which means, I have to be oncall for a week every month and be generally available 24/7, at other times.</description></item><item><title>checklists: an operational gift</title><link>https://sricola.com/blog/checklists/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sricola.com/blog/checklists/</guid><description>No production operation is too small or too big for a checklist. Similarly, no situation is too strenuous for one. Always write one — it ensures smooth process! At BuzzFeed we love lists. I mean, we helped pioneer the list format! Lists are easily digestible and are clear and concise in their meaning. They are no replacement for a long form read, but hey, nobody’s got time to read a leather bound novel by a fireplace during a production operation.</description></item><item><title>The Most Wanted iPhone 7 Feature Nobody Talks About</title><link>https://sricola.com/blog/most-wanted-iphone-feature/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sricola.com/blog/most-wanted-iphone-feature/</guid><description>Anyone who even remotely follows any technology oriented blog or website is probably well aware of the plethora of rumors and leaks that happen before any major consumer product announcement. This is more so true for rumors and leaks related to Apple. Partly to blame(credit?) for their secrecy when it comes to un-announced products — Apple somehow evokes consumer emotions — on levels that are unheard of. When was the last time CNN covered a queue of people waiting outside the Samsung store, days before a phone launch?</description></item><item><title>An ode to a dying friend. Blackberry, you will be missed!</title><link>https://sricola.com/blog/an-ode-to-a-dying-friend/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2013 18:55:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sricola.com/blog/an-ode-to-a-dying-friend/</guid><description>I hold Blackberry close to my heart. I accepted my first real job offer on a Blackberry. I read the words “I love you” for the first time ever, in a Blackberry messenger message. I took to obsessively taking photos of food on a Blackberry. I got addicted to twitter on a Blackberry. The list goes on … I broke up with Blackberrys a while back. But, as with any other past relationship, I never meant ill.</description></item></channel></rss>