<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>travel on Sri Ray | sricola</title><link>https://sricola.com/categories/travel/</link><description>Recent content in travel on Sri Ray | sricola</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sricola.com/categories/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>NYC MTA Ridership over COVID-19</title><link>https://sricola.com/blog/mta/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sricola.com/blog/mta/</guid><description>The New York City Transit Authority (MTA) releases weekly data on the number of entries and exits at each of its subway stations. This analysis is based on the data retrieved from the following weeks
Week of January 19 - &amp;ldquo;normal week&amp;rdquo; before the outbreak, used as a control Week of March 8 - week before NYC placed various restrictions Week of March 15 What data is being analysed The data is based on entries into the specified stations, during the timeframe noted.</description></item><item><title>10 Things I have learnt after flying a Million Miles</title><link>https://sricola.com/blog/after-a-million-miles/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sricola.com/blog/after-a-million-miles/</guid><description>Lifetime Flight Map (twitter.com/sricola)
Be kind to your cabin crew. They literally have your lives in their control. Service is their secondary job — getting you safely from A to B is their primary. And they do their jobs 100% of the time. On the topic of cabin crew, they only get paid on block time — door close to door open. Pre boarding help / stowing your luggage etc is literally volunteer time.</description></item><item><title>Digital Nomad Life: tech in my backpack</title><link>https://sricola.com/blog/tech-in-my-backpack/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sricola.com/blog/tech-in-my-backpack/</guid><description>Anything that goes into my backpack has to earn its place there.
This past year, I have lived in 6 continents, 17 countries, 7 time zones and 21 cities. All this while working a full time job, remotely.
Work is my primary goal. Work is what enables me to live this life. So obviously, being connected is the center of my focus. Additionally, I am part of the Infrastructure team at BuzzFeed, which means, I have to be oncall for a week every month and be generally available 24/7, at other times.</description></item><item><title>2015: In Black and White</title><link>https://sricola.com/blog/2015-black-and-white/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sricola.com/blog/2015-black-and-white/</guid><description>Aachen Cathedral, Aachen, Germany Gateway of India, Bombay (Mumbai), India Dhobi Ghat, the biggest laundromat in the world, Bombay (Mumbai), India City Hall, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, United States of America The only double decker tram system in the world, Hong Kong SAR, People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China Sunrise at 40,000 feet, on approach into London, United Kingdom Locks of Love, Seoul, Republic of Korea Manhattan, New York, NY, United States of America Union Station, Washington, District of Columbia, United States of America Forrest Fires, California, United States of America Skyline of Seattle, Washignton, United States of America View of the skyline from the Bund, Shanghai, People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China Golden Gate Bridge, San Francisco, California, United States of America Muir Woods Redwood Trees, California, United States of America Looking down Market Street, San Francisco, California Crater Lake, Oregon, United States of America Wine Barrels, Benzinger Family Wineries, NAPA, California, United States of America New York Harbor, New York, NY, United States of America Hayden Planetarium, New York, NY, United States of America Grand Bazaar, Istanbul, Turkey Mt.</description></item><item><title>A Town in Two Countries - The Baarle Problem</title><link>https://sricola.com/blog/baarle-hertog-baarle-nassau/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2014 18:55:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sricola.com/blog/baarle-hertog-baarle-nassau/</guid><description>With a combined population of less than 8000 - Baarle-Hertog and Baarle-Nassau are off the beaten tourist path. I will admit that not many people would crave to go there. Between getting high in Amsterdam and the beers of Belgium - it is not very uncommon for tourists to completely skip this little gem of International Co-operation.
It is a situation that arose out of a land swap deal during the monarch days of Belgium and the Netherlands.</description></item></channel></rss>